Why do farmers grow crops outside in fields when we can stack them vertically?
既然我们可以垂直种植作物，为什么农民还要在户外田地里种植呢？
The idea of vertical farming was first proposed in 1999.
垂直农业这一概念最早于1999年被提出。
It was seen as a way to save space, reduce air miles and transform old and abandoned buildings, like warehouses.
它被视为是一种节省空间、缩短空运距离、改造仓库等老旧废弃建筑的方式。
In 2021, Fortune Business Insights valued the global vertical farming market at 3.47 billion dollars.
2021年，《财富商业洞察》估算全球垂直农业市场规模为34.7亿美元。
Now, however, this industry is under threat, partly due to rising energy costs.
然而如今，该行业正面临威胁，部分原因是能源成本上涨。
According to the magazine Science Focus, vertical farming gives ten times the yield of conventional outdoor farming.
《科学焦点》杂志称，垂直农业的产量是传统户外农业的十倍。
However, in order for crops to grow using this method, plants are placed in a controlled environment, grown not under the Sun, but under LED lights and watered with recycled water pumped on a closed-loop system.
但采用这种方式种植作物时，植物需置于可控环境中，不靠阳光生长，而是在LED灯下培育，并通过闭环系统循环供水灌溉。
Unfortunately, energy prices have risen across the globe.
遗憾的是，全球能源价格普遍上涨。
Therefore, this reliance on electricity has meant the last few years have not been easy for the industry.
因此，对电力的高度依赖使得该行业过去几年处境艰难。
Cindy van Rijswick, from the Dutch research firm RaboResearch, has estimated that operational costs for a vertical farm are around 15% higher now compared to 18 months ago.
荷兰研究公司RaboResearch的辛迪·范·赖斯维克估计，与18个月前相比，如今垂直农场的运营成本高出约15%。
Infarm, Europe's largest vertical farming company, made around 500 employees redundant back in November 2022 because they needed to downsize.
欧洲最大垂直农业公司Infarm在2022年11月裁员约500名员工以缩小规模。
They blamed higher operating costs due to energy increases as one reason for the layoffs.
该公司将能源涨价导致运营成本上升列为裁员原因之一。
Another issue related to the cost-of-living crisis and affecting vertical farming is the type of produce grown.
另一个与生活成本危机相关、且影响垂直农业的问题是其种植的农产品种类。
This includes herbs such as basil, as well as salad leaves and leafy greens.
这类作物包括罗勒等香草，以及沙拉叶和绿叶蔬菜。
Compared to traditionally farmed ingredients, like onions and carrots, these products are more expensive so could be less in demand as consumers watch their spending more.
与洋葱、胡萝卜等传统种植食材相比，这些产品价格更高，因此在消费者更注重开支的情况下，需求可能会下降。
So, it seems a future with food grown under LED lights is looking less and less bright.
如此看来，靠LED灯种植粮食的未来，前景似乎越来越黯淡。